The Why of Fry
FRY:Delivery boy Philip J. Fry,
reporting for duty.
ZOIDBERG:Dr. Zoidberg, soaking in brine.
Ah. . . .
FRY:What is the meaning of this?
We've got a delivery. Let's move!
FRY:Amy, mission profile.
FRY:Interesting. Interesting.
FRY:-Dr. Zoidberg, mission bag?
ZOIDBERG:-Packed and ready, sir.
FRY:What's this? This is the same
toy surprise I got last time.
FRY:I can't work under these conditions.
And without me, there is no mission.
FRY:-I am the mission.
LEELA (SHOUTING):-We're back from the mission.
FRY:What? You went without me?
BENDER (SHOUTING):You were looking up curse words
in the dictionary.
BENDER (SHOUTING):-It seemed like a better use of your time.
FRY:-But I'm the delivery boy.
LEELA:-Don't worry, everything went fine.
BENDER:-Better than usual.
LEELA:We got medals.
LEELA:Good work, team. We really
pulled together on this one.
Whoo-hoo!
They got medals.
FRY:I'm real sorry I missed the mission.
FRY:-You might have needed me.
BENDER:-Nope.
FRY:-But if I'd been there, l--
BENDER:-Nope!
-Look--
BENDER:-Nope.
FRY:-Bender's great.
FRY:Leela, let me make it up
by taking you out for dinner tonight.
LEELA:-Nope, I've got a date with Chaz.
FRY:-Chaz?
LEELA:I met him at that charity cockfight
last week. He's the mayor's aide.
BENDER:-Oh, you go, mutant girl.
-Oh.
LEELA:-I do go. He's a very important man.
FRY:-So? I'm just as important as him.
FRY:It's just that the kind of importance
I have, it doesn't matter if I don't do it.
[PURRING]
FRY:Oh, I'm nobody.
FRY:There are guys in the background
of "Mary Worth" comics. . .
FRY:. . .who are more important than me.
BENDER:Buck up, meat loaf. Bender
will take you out and cheer you up.
BENDER:What do you want to do? And I mean
anything. You have the power.
BENDER:Name it and I'm there. You the man.
FRY:-Well, okay. Let's go bowling.
BENDER:-Nah.
ELZAR:Table for two? Step right this way.
CHAZ:I'm afraid we don't have a reservation,
but as you can see. . .
CHAZ:. . .I'm the mayor's aide.
Table for two, please.
ELZAR:Okay, then.
-Hey!
CHAZ:-It's okay, my man. . .
CHAZ:. . .I got you covered on your next
health inspection.
ELZAR:Oh, I really appreciate that,
Mr. Mayor's Aide. Here you go.
ELZAR:Compliments of the house.
LEELA:Wow! Free bread at a restaurant!
ls there anything you can't do?
CHAZ:-I can't fail the mayor. Not ever.
FRY:-Oh.
[BELL RINGS]
FRY:-Oh, jeez, I better not let Leela see me.
LEELA:-Hey, I hear Fry.
LEELA:-Boy, am I glad you're here.
FRY:-You are?
FRY:Things aren't working out
with what's-his-name?
LEELA:Actually, they are.
LEELA:Confidentially, I might not make it back
to my apartment tonight.
LEELA:-Could you walk Nibbler for me?
FRY:-Ah. . . .
LEELA:And bring a baggie, in case
he drops a steamer. Have a great night.
[MUMBLING]
FRY:Oh, no. Please, no!
FRY:Perfect.
[GROANING]
[SIREN WAILING]
SMITTY:Whoa. Smells like a 289 in progress.
URL:Failure to scoop. Oh, yeah.
FRY:Wait, I'm trying.
It weighs as much as 1 000 suns.
CHAZ:Don't worry. I'll pull some strings,
see if I can't get you tried as a juvenile.
LEELA:Oh, Chaz.
[SIGHS]
FRY:I'm as worthless as this trashcan.
TRASHCAN:You think I'm as worthless as you?
TRASHCAN:Try catching garbage in your head
and raising six kids, you dumb townie.
FRY:Oh, Nibbler, at least
I'm important to you. . .
FRY:. . .even if it's only
because I clean up your poop.
NIBBLER:The poop eradication
is but one aspect of your importance.
[SCREAMS]
FRY:-Did you just talk?
NIBBLER:-Indeed. . .
NIBBLER:. . .and I have other
amazing powers as well.
FRY:Like what?
FRY:-Are you my mommy?
NIBBLER:-Negative.
[GROANING]
FIONA:-Welcome, Lord Nibbler.
NIBBLER:-Welcome acknowledged.
NIBBLER:I bring with me The Mighty One.
FRY:Uh?
KEN:At last, our centuries upon centuries
of waiting have achieved fruition.
FRY:Aren't you a fuzzy little guy?
[PURRING]
KEN:Stop that! Please, Your Mightiness.
FRY:"Mightiness"? Are you off your nut? I got
kidnapped by a bunch of guinea pigs.
[GIBBERING]
KEN:-Does he not know?
NIBBLER:-He does not know.
FIONA:-He knows not?
NIBBLER:-Knows not does he.
NIBBLONIAN:-Not he knows?
KEN:-Enough!
KEN:Fry, it is my duty to inform you
that the fate of humanity. . .
KEN:. . .the fate of our race,
indeed, the fate of all that exists. . .
KEN:. . .and ever will exist, rests with you.
KEN:You are the single most
important person in the universe.
FRY:Oh, snap.
NIBBLER:On this auspicious occasion, let the horn
of eternity cut a thunderous blast.
[MUFFLED BLOWING]
FIONA:The Feast of a Thousand Beasts
is begun.
[BURPING]
NIBBLONIAN:-You gonna eat that?
FRY:-Maybe later.
KEN:The time has come to discuss
matters of the gravest importance.
NIBBLER:Fry, do you remember
some months ago. . .
NIBBLER:. . .when Earth was attacked
by Flying Brains?
FRY:I remember the dancing stomachs. That
might've been a Mylanta commercial.
FRY:Wait, the Brains! I do remember. . .
FRY:. . .but no one else does.
They said I was crazy.
KEN:You remember because you were. . .
KEN:. . .the only one immune
to the Brains' mental attack.
FRY:Because I'm so smart?
[CHUCKLING]
KEN:Oh, my.
KEN:Anyway, your immunity is due to the
fact that you lack the delta brain wave.
KEN:It's a genetic abnormality, which resulted
when you went back in time. . .
KEN:. . .and performed certain actions
which made you your own grandfather.
FRY:I did do the nasty in the past-y.
NIBBLER:Verily, and that past nastification
is what shields you from the Brains.
NIBBLER:You are the last hope of the universe.
FRY:So I really am important?
How I feel when I'm drunk is correct?
KEN:Yes, except the Dave Matthews Band
doesn't rock.
KEN:For a thousand years, the evil Brains
have been constructing. . .
KEN:. . .the lnfo-Sphere,
a giant memory bank. . .
KEN:. . .twice the size of three
ordinary memory banks.
FRY:-What's evil about that?
FIONA:-They plan to collect. . .
FIONA:. . .all the information in the universe
and store it within the sphere.
FRY:-They're trying to learn things?
FIONA:-Right.
FRY:-Those bastards!
NIBBLER:-Being brains, they feel compelled. . .
NIBBLER:. . .to know everything,
and soon they will.
FRY:-I'm as mad as I've ever been.
KEN:-Once their task is complete. . .
KEN:. . .they will ensure that
no new information arises. . .
KEN:. . .in the only way possible.
By destroying the universe.
FRY:Now it's personal.
FIONA:Your mission is to infiltrate
the lnfo-Sphere. . .
FIONA:. . .and plant this quantum
interface bomb. . .
FIONA:. . .blasting them into an alternate
universe from which there is no return.
NIBBLER:Then outrun the blast
on this Scooty-Puff Junior.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
FRY:Okay, let's go through
this once more from the--
[YELLS]
FRY:-Brains!
KEN [ON SCREEN]:-Fear not, Mighty One.
KEN [ON SCREEN]:Your missing brain wave
makes you invisible to them.
KEN [ON SCREEN]:-So long as you avoid intense thinking.
FRY:-Sorry, what? I wasn't paying attention.
KEN [ON SCREEN]:-That is most wise.
FRY:-Who?
KEN [ON SCREEN]:In a few seconds,
the Brains will finish scanning...
KEN [ON SCREEN]:... the last bits of information
in the universe.
COMPUTER: Beavers mate for life.
Eleven greater than four.
For quality carpets,
visit Caplan 's Carpet Warehouse.
KEN [ON SCREEN]:Now the lnfo-Sphere will open
its protective crust...
KEN [ON SCREEN]:...so as to scan itself,
completing its thousand-year task.
FIONA [ON SCREEN]:This is your one chance to enter
the sphere. Scoot. Scoot now!
[GRUNTING]
FRY:I'm at the input console.
FRY:I'm nervous, and I've got
brain in my butt crack.
NIBBLER [ON SCREEN]:Roger.
KEN [ON SCREEN]:Once you press the detonator, you will
have 60 seconds for an exciting escape.
FRY:Hey, wait. This Brain knows
about everything, right?
KEN [ON SCREEN]:It will soon. That's why you're
supposed to be setting off a bomb.
FRY:I can't pass up
a chance to learn the answers. . .
FRY:. . .to the greatest questions of all time.
FRY:Is it true that postage-stamp
glue is made of--?
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:MASTER BRAIN:
Correct, toad mucus.
[TOAD CROAKS]
KEN [ON SCREEN]:There's no time for this.
Activate the bomb.
FRY:Wait, wait, wait.
What really killed the dinosaurs?
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:MASTER BRAIN:
Me!
COMPUTER:
Unauthorized data access.
Uh-oh.
GIANT BRAIN:Detecting trace amounts
of mental activity.
GIANT BRAIN:Possibly a dead weasel
or a cartoon viewer.
FRY:Ew! Gross, cut it out.
BRAIN #1:Odd, he is immune to our psionic attack.
BRAIN #2:Impossible. We're an ambitious
young squad with everything to prove.
GIANT BRAIN:It appears we are in the presence
of the fabled one. . .
GIANT BRAIN:. . .but without his Scooty-Puff Junior,
he cannot escape.
[BRAIN CHUCKLING]
BRAIN #2:A quantum interface bomb?
Are you insane in the membrane?
FRY:You got it, Poindexter.
BRAIN #1:Oh, not good.
COMPUTER VOICE:COMPUTER: Detonation in T-minus
60 Earth seconds.
[BEEPING]
BRAIN #3:You fool! You will be transported
to the other universe with us.
BRAIN #3:Trapped there for all eternity.
BRAIN #1:We'll form a tight clique
that you won't be part of.
FRY:Well, at least I did one
important thing with my life. . .
FRY:. . .Ieading good to victory over evil.
-Yeah!
KEN [ON SCREEN]:-Exactly!
GIANT BRAIN:The Nibblonians? Good? Ha.
GIANT BRAIN:During your last moments in this
universe, perhaps you should query. . .
GIANT BRAIN:. . .our database concerning the night
of December 31 , 1 999.
FRY:-The day I got frozen? What about it?
NIBBLER [ON SCREEN]:-No.
NIBBLER [ON SCREEN]:Don 't ask about that.
It would be boring.
FRY:-Forget it, then.
GIANT BRAIN:-Query!
Okay.
FRY:What happened to me, Philip J. Fry,
on the night of December 31 , 1 999?
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:Clarification request. Are you
the Philip J. Fry from Earth. . .
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:. . .or the Philip J. Fry from
Hovering Squid World 97A?
GIANT BRAIN:Earth, you fat idiot. Hurry up.
FRY [ON SCREEN]:Hello? Pizza delivery for...
FRY [ON SCREEN]:... "I. C. Wiener"? Oh, crud.
FRY:Uh, I can't believe how fat I look.
FRY:Oh, Nibbler's there. Wait. What?!
[SCREAMS]
FRY [ON SCREEN]:FRY:
What the--?
FRY:I-- I don't understand.
You made me go in the freezer tube?
COMPUTER VOICE:COMPUTER:
Detonation in T-minus 15 seconds.
FRY:You little runts froze me.
You took away my life.
NIBBLER [ON SCREEN]:-We can explain.
FRY:-No, you can't. Shut your adorable trap.
NIBBLER [ON SCREEN]:We had no choice. You were
the only one who could help us.
NIBBLER [ON SCREEN]:What is one life weighed
against the entire universe?
FRY (CRYING):But it was my life.
COMPUTER VOICE:Detonation in two, one--
COMPUTER VOICE:Will the owner of a white
Pontiac Firebird--? Oh, never mind, zero!
GIANT BRAIN:Well, here we are,
trapped for eternity.
BRAIN #2:-We could sing "American Pie. "
FRY:-Go ahead, I deserve it.
FRY:I wish those stupid raccoons
had never brought me to the future.
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:I have shocking data
relevant to this conversation.
GIANT BRAIN:We don't care, you dope.
GIANT BRAIN:We're in another universe.
You're not in charge.
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:It is possible for the Philip Fry to resume
his life on December 31 , 1 999.
FRY:Really? I can go back in time?
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:MASTER BRAIN:
There is a nexus point. . .
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:. . .at the space-time where you
entered the cryogenic tube.
INFOSPHERE BRAIN:You, and only you, can return there.
GIANT BRAIN:Interesting. You could
stop the Nibblonian. . .
GIANT BRAIN:. . .from pushing you
into the cryogenic tube.
FRY:That is interesting. Why?
GIANT BRAIN:It will be as if you
never came to the future.
GIANT BRAIN:You will have your life back,
and we will succeed. . .
GIANT BRAIN:. . .in our plan to understand
and destroy the universe.
FRY:-Everybody wins.
BRAIN: The human returns to the past!
NARRATOR:NARRATOR:
Meanwhile....
LEELA:I love rocket skating,
but the wait is always so long.
LEELA:Poor Fry once stood in line six hours
just to get me a ticket.
CHAZ:Six hours? Sounds like a real nobody. . .
CHAZ:. . .but now it's time for somebody
and some chick he's with to go skating.
LEELA:-You reserved the whole rink?
CHAZ:-Yep, buzzed ahead. . .
CHAZ:. . .Iet them know whose aide was
coming by. The mayor's, that's whose.
LEELA:Oh, Chaz!
SALLY:Mr. Vogel, I thought
we was going skating.
VOGEL:No, we're not important enough.
VOGEL:Everybody just hold hands until the
bus driver comes back from his haircut.
LEELA:-Oh, let's let those kids skate with us.
CHAZ:-What? Seriously?
CHAZ:-I'm trying to impress you with my clout.
LEELA:-I know, and it's working.
LEELA:But think how much skating
would mean to those kids.
ORPHAN:We came here instead of eating today.
LEELA:This might be their only chance
to skate here their whole lives.
LEELA:-Who are we to say they can't?
CHAZ:-The mayor's aide and his badge.
CHAZ:Beat it, kids! Come back
when you got connections.
All right, little ones. . .
VOGEL:. . .back to the orphanarium. You can
slide around the gym in your socks.
SALLY:What socks?
CHAZ:So am I gonna get lucky
tonight, or what?
[MUMBLING]
FRY:I hope your calculations are correct.
GIANT BRAIN:Our calculations are always correct,
for we are gigantic brains.
BRAIN #2:Initiate space-time transfer.
NIBBLER:I hereby place an order
for one cheese pizza.
PANUCCI [ON PHONE]:MAN:
One pie, nothing good on it. Name?
NIBBLER:I-period-C-period Wiener.
PANUCCI [ON PHONE]:Talk a little louder. It sounds like
you got some kind of tiny head on you.
[DOOR OPENS]
PAST FRY:Hello? Pizza delivery for. . .
PAST FRY:. . . "I.C. Wiener"? Oh, crud.
FUTURE FRY:Gotcha!
NIBBLER:-I don't understand.
FUTURE FRY:-Yes, you do.
FUTURE FRY:You came back in time
to knock me into that freezer. . .
FUTURE FRY:. . .and now I came back to stop you.
NIBBLER:I did not come back in time.
My people lack that ability.
FUTURE FRY:But I know you in the future.
I cleaned your poop.
NIBBLER:Quite possible. We live long
and are celebrated poopers.
NIBBLER:You will meet me
when I'm 1 000 years older.
FUTURE FRY:Not if you don't freeze me.
NIBBLER:Please, our sages foresee
that in 1 000 years. . .
NIBBLER:. . .for one moment, the fate
of the universe will depend on you.
NIBBLER:Since you will not live that long,
I must freeze you now.
FUTURE FRY:-Well, why couldn't you just ask me?
NIBBLER:-We were afraid you would refuse.
FUTURE FRY:Of course not, I love the future.
NIBBLER (CHOKING):Then why are you
choking me right now?
FUTURE FRY:Because I don't like being used.
NIBBLER:Well, now it's your choice. Is there
nothing in the future worth saving?
FUTURE FRY:Hmm. Leela, but she doesn't
think much of me.
NIBBLER:Oh, she must be The Other.
FUTURE FRY:What?
NIBBLER:You must not give up on her.
NIBBLER:I am stationed on a distant world
known as Virgon Six. . .
NIBBLER:. . .but if you return to the future,
I will transfer to Earth. . .
NIBBLER:. . .to give you what help I can.
FUTURE FRY:ALL: Ten, nine, eight, seven. . . .
-You think I had a chance with Leela?
NIBBLER:You must choose.
The present or the future?
NIBBLER:To save yourself or save Leela.
ALL:
One!
FUTURE FRY:Yes! Here I come, future.
Oh, no, wait!
FUTURE FRY:I'm gonna get trapped
in the lnfo-Sphere again.
FUTURE FRY:Just remember that
Scooty-Puff Junior sucks!
NIBBLER:In 1 000 years, I'll get right on it.
NARRATOR:NARRATOR: And so 1000 years later,
Fry once again...
NARRATOR:...infiltrated the lnfo-Sphere
and set off his amazing bomb.
NARRATOR:Only this time....
NIBBLER:Thank you for saving the universe, Fry.
NIBBLER:-Here.
FRY:-Oh, thanks.
FRY:If you ever need a savior again, just ask.
NIBBLER:Oh, we will. We will.
FRY:I can't wait to tell
everyone what happened.
NIBBLER:Yes. Incidentally,
I need to remain undercover. . .
NIBBLER:. . .so I'm blanking your memory.
FRY:Did everything just taste
purple for a second?
FRY:Oh, well, let's go home,
you dumb poop machine.
[GIBBERING]
LEELA:-Bender, would you do the honors?
BENDER:-With gusto.
FRY:Hey, Leela. I guess I got this for you.
LEELA:Oh, thank you.
LEELA:You know what?
I don't care if you're not. . .
LEELA:. . .the most important person
in the universe.
LEELA:It really makes me happy
to see you right now.
FRY:Then I am the most important
person in the universe.
FRY (OVER CREDITS):Yes!