The Why of Fry
Delivery boy Philip J. Fry,
reporting for duty.
Dr. Zoidberg, soaking in brine.
Ah. . . .
What is the meaning of this?
We've got a delivery. Let's move!
Amy, mission profile.
Interesting. Interesting.
-Dr. Zoidberg, mission bag?
-Packed and ready, sir.
What's this? This is the same
toy surprise I got last time.
I can't work under these conditions.
And without me, there is no mission.
-I am the mission.
-We're back from the mission.
What? You went without me?
You were looking up curse words
in the dictionary.
-It seemed like a better use of your time.
-But I'm the delivery boy.
-Don't worry, everything went fine.
-Better than usual.
We got medals.
Good work, team. We really
pulled together on this one.
Whoo-hoo!
They got medals.
I'm real sorry I missed the mission.
-You might have needed me.
-Nope.
-But if I'd been there, l--
-Nope!
-Look--
-Nope.
-Bender's great.
Leela, let me make it up
by taking you out for dinner tonight.
-Nope, I've got a date with Chaz.
-Chaz?
I met him at that charity cockfight
last week. He's the mayor's aide.
-Oh, you go, mutant girl.
-Oh.
-I do go. He's a very important man.
-So? I'm just as important as him.
It's just that the kind of importance
I have, it doesn't matter if I don't do it.
[PURRING]
Oh, I'm nobody.
There are guys in the background
of "Mary Worth" comics. . .
. . .who are more important than me.
Buck up, meat loaf. Bender
will take you out and cheer you up.
What do you want to do? And I mean
anything. You have the power.
Name it and I'm there. You the man.
-Well, okay. Let's go bowling.
-Nah.
Table for two? Step right this way.
I'm afraid we don't have a reservation,
but as you can see. . .
. . .I'm the mayor's aide.
Table for two, please.
Okay, then.
-Hey!
-It's okay, my man. . .
. . .I got you covered on your next
health inspection.
Oh, I really appreciate that,
Mr. Mayor's Aide. Here you go.
Compliments of the house.
Wow! Free bread at a restaurant!
ls there anything you can't do?
-I can't fail the mayor. Not ever.
-Oh.
[BELL RINGS]
-Oh, jeez, I better not let Leela see me.
-Hey, I hear Fry.
-Boy, am I glad you're here.
-You are?
Things aren't working out
with what's-his-name?
Actually, they are.
Confidentially, I might not make it back
to my apartment tonight.
-Could you walk Nibbler for me?
-Ah. . . .
And bring a baggie, in case
he drops a steamer. Have a great night.
[MUMBLING]
Oh, no. Please, no!
Perfect.
[GROANING]
[SIREN WAILING]
Whoa. Smells like a 289 in progress.
Failure to scoop. Oh, yeah.
Wait, I'm trying.
It weighs as much as 1 000 suns.
Don't worry. I'll pull some strings,
see if I can't get you tried as a juvenile.
Oh, Chaz.
[SIGHS]
I'm as worthless as this trashcan.
You think I'm as worthless as you?
Try catching garbage in your head
and raising six kids, you dumb townie.
Oh, Nibbler, at least
I'm important to you. . .
. . .even if it's only
because I clean up your poop.
The poop eradication
is but one aspect of your importance.
[SCREAMS]
-Did you just talk?
-Indeed. . .
. . .and I have other
amazing powers as well.
Like what?
-Are you my mommy?
-Negative.
[GROANING]
-Welcome, Lord Nibbler.
-Welcome acknowledged.
I bring with me The Mighty One.
Uh?
At last, our centuries upon centuries
of waiting have achieved fruition.
Aren't you a fuzzy little guy?
[PURRING]
Stop that! Please, Your Mightiness.
"Mightiness"? Are you off your nut? I got
kidnapped by a bunch of guinea pigs.
[GIBBERING]
-Does he not know?
-He does not know.
-He knows not?
-Knows not does he.
-Not he knows?
-Enough!
Fry, it is my duty to inform you
that the fate of humanity. . .
. . .the fate of our race,
indeed, the fate of all that exists. . .
. . .and ever will exist, rests with you.
You are the single most
important person in the universe.
Oh, snap.
On this auspicious occasion, let the horn
of eternity cut a thunderous blast.
[MUFFLED BLOWING]
The Feast of a Thousand Beasts
is begun.
[BURPING]
-You gonna eat that?
-Maybe later.
The time has come to discuss
matters of the gravest importance.
Fry, do you remember
some months ago. . .
. . .when Earth was attacked
by Flying Brains?
I remember the dancing stomachs. That
might've been a Mylanta commercial.
Wait, the Brains! I do remember. . .
. . .but no one else does.
They said I was crazy.
You remember because you were. . .
. . .the only one immune
to the Brains' mental attack.
Because I'm so smart?
[CHUCKLING]
Oh, my.
Anyway, your immunity is due to the
fact that you lack the delta brain wave.
It's a genetic abnormality, which resulted
when you went back in time. . .
. . .and performed certain actions
which made you your own grandfather.
I did do the nasty in the past-y.
Verily, and that past nastification
is what shields you from the Brains.
You are the last hope of the universe.
So I really am important?
How I feel when I'm drunk is correct?
Yes, except the Dave Matthews Band
doesn't rock.
For a thousand years, the evil Brains
have been constructing. . .
. . .the lnfo-Sphere,
a giant memory bank. . .
. . .twice the size of three
ordinary memory banks.
-What's evil about that?
-They plan to collect. . .
. . .all the information in the universe
and store it within the sphere.
-They're trying to learn things?
-Right.
-Those bastards!
-Being brains, they feel compelled. . .
. . .to know everything,
and soon they will.
-I'm as mad as I've ever been.
-Once their task is complete. . .
. . .they will ensure that
no new information arises. . .
. . .in the only way possible.
By destroying the universe.
Now it's personal.
Your mission is to infiltrate
the lnfo-Sphere. . .
. . .and plant this quantum
interface bomb. . .
. . .blasting them into an alternate
universe from which there is no return.
Then outrun the blast
on this Scooty-Puff Junior.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
Okay, let's go through
this once more from the--
[YELLS]
-Brains!
-Fear not, Mighty One.
Your missing brain wave
makes you invisible to them.
-So long as you avoid intense thinking.
-Sorry, what? I wasn't paying attention.
-That is most wise.
-Who?
In a few seconds,
the Brains will finish scanning...
... the last bits of information
in the universe.
COMPUTER: Beavers mate for life.
Eleven greater than four.
For quality carpets,
visit Caplan 's Carpet Warehouse.
Now the lnfo-Sphere will open
its protective crust...
...so as to scan itself,
completing its thousand-year task.
This is your one chance to enter
the sphere. Scoot. Scoot now!
[GRUNTING]
I'm at the input console.
I'm nervous, and I've got
brain in my butt crack.
Roger.
Once you press the detonator, you will
have 60 seconds for an exciting escape.
Hey, wait. This Brain knows
about everything, right?
It will soon. That's why you're
supposed to be setting off a bomb.
I can't pass up
a chance to learn the answers. . .
. . .to the greatest questions of all time.
Is it true that postage-stamp
glue is made of--?
MASTER BRAIN:
Correct, toad mucus.
[TOAD CROAKS]
There's no time for this.
Activate the bomb.
Wait, wait, wait.
What really killed the dinosaurs?
MASTER BRAIN:
Me!
COMPUTER:
Unauthorized data access.
Uh-oh.
Detecting trace amounts
of mental activity.
Possibly a dead weasel
or a cartoon viewer.
Ew! Gross, cut it out.
Odd, he is immune to our psionic attack.
Impossible. We're an ambitious
young squad with everything to prove.
It appears we are in the presence
of the fabled one. . .
. . .but without his Scooty-Puff Junior,
he cannot escape.
[BRAIN CHUCKLING]
A quantum interface bomb?
Are you insane in the membrane?
You got it, Poindexter.
Oh, not good.
COMPUTER: Detonation in T-minus
60 Earth seconds.
[BEEPING]
You fool! You will be transported
to the other universe with us.
Trapped there for all eternity.
We'll form a tight clique
that you won't be part of.
Well, at least I did one
important thing with my life. . .
. . .Ieading good to victory over evil.
-Yeah!
-Exactly!
The Nibblonians? Good? Ha.
During your last moments in this
universe, perhaps you should query. . .
. . .our database concerning the night
of December 31 , 1 999.
-The day I got frozen? What about it?
-No.
Don 't ask about that.
It would be boring.
-Forget it, then.
-Query!
Okay.
What happened to me, Philip J. Fry,
on the night of December 31 , 1 999?
Clarification request. Are you
the Philip J. Fry from Earth. . .
. . .or the Philip J. Fry from
Hovering Squid World 97A?
Earth, you fat idiot. Hurry up.
Hello? Pizza delivery for...
... "I. C. Wiener"? Oh, crud.
Uh, I can't believe how fat I look.
Oh, Nibbler's there. Wait. What?!
[SCREAMS]
FRY:
What the--?
I-- I don't understand.
You made me go in the freezer tube?
COMPUTER:
Detonation in T-minus 15 seconds.
You little runts froze me.
You took away my life.
-We can explain.
-No, you can't. Shut your adorable trap.
We had no choice. You were
the only one who could help us.
What is one life weighed
against the entire universe?
But it was my life.
Detonation in two, one--
Will the owner of a white
Pontiac Firebird--? Oh, never mind, zero!
Well, here we are,
trapped for eternity.
-We could sing "American Pie. "
-Go ahead, I deserve it.
I wish those stupid raccoons
had never brought me to the future.
I have shocking data
relevant to this conversation.
We don't care, you dope.
We're in another universe.
You're not in charge.
It is possible for the Philip Fry to resume
his life on December 31 , 1 999.
Really? I can go back in time?
MASTER BRAIN:
There is a nexus point. . .
. . .at the space-time where you
entered the cryogenic tube.
You, and only you, can return there.
Interesting. You could
stop the Nibblonian. . .
. . .from pushing you
into the cryogenic tube.
That is interesting. Why?
It will be as if you
never came to the future.
You will have your life back,
and we will succeed. . .
. . .in our plan to understand
and destroy the universe.
-Everybody wins.
BRAIN: The human returns to the past!
NARRATOR:
Meanwhile....
I love rocket skating,
but the wait is always so long.
Poor Fry once stood in line six hours
just to get me a ticket.
Six hours? Sounds like a real nobody. . .
. . .but now it's time for somebody
and some chick he's with to go skating.
-You reserved the whole rink?
-Yep, buzzed ahead. . .
. . .Iet them know whose aide was
coming by. The mayor's, that's whose.
Oh, Chaz!
Mr. Vogel, I thought
we was going skating.
No, we're not important enough.
Everybody just hold hands until the
bus driver comes back from his haircut.
-Oh, let's let those kids skate with us.
-What? Seriously?
-I'm trying to impress you with my clout.
-I know, and it's working.
But think how much skating
would mean to those kids.
We came here instead of eating today.
This might be their only chance
to skate here their whole lives.
-Who are we to say they can't?
-The mayor's aide and his badge.
Beat it, kids! Come back
when you got connections.
All right, little ones. . .
. . .back to the orphanarium. You can
slide around the gym in your socks.
What socks?
So am I gonna get lucky
tonight, or what?
[MUMBLING]
I hope your calculations are correct.
Our calculations are always correct,
for we are gigantic brains.
Initiate space-time transfer.
I hereby place an order
for one cheese pizza.
MAN:
One pie, nothing good on it. Name?
I-period-C-period Wiener.
Talk a little louder. It sounds like
you got some kind of tiny head on you.
[DOOR OPENS]
Hello? Pizza delivery for. . .
. . . "I.C. Wiener"? Oh, crud.
Gotcha!
-I don't understand.
-Yes, you do.
You came back in time
to knock me into that freezer. . .
. . .and now I came back to stop you.
I did not come back in time.
My people lack that ability.
But I know you in the future.
I cleaned your poop.
Quite possible. We live long
and are celebrated poopers.
You will meet me
when I'm 1 000 years older.
Not if you don't freeze me.
Please, our sages foresee
that in 1 000 years. . .
. . .for one moment, the fate
of the universe will depend on you.
Since you will not live that long,
I must freeze you now.
-Well, why couldn't you just ask me?
-We were afraid you would refuse.
Of course not, I love the future.
Then why are you
choking me right now?
Because I don't like being used.
Well, now it's your choice. Is there
nothing in the future worth saving?
Hmm. Leela, but she doesn't
think much of me.
Oh, she must be The Other.
What?
You must not give up on her.
I am stationed on a distant world
known as Virgon Six. . .
. . .but if you return to the future,
I will transfer to Earth. . .
. . .to give you what help I can.
ALL: Ten, nine, eight, seven. . . .
-You think I had a chance with Leela?
You must choose.
The present or the future?
To save yourself or save Leela.
ALL:
One!
Yes! Here I come, future.
Oh, no, wait!
I'm gonna get trapped
in the lnfo-Sphere again.
Just remember that
Scooty-Puff Junior sucks!
In 1 000 years, I'll get right on it.
NARRATOR: And so 1000 years later,
Fry once again...
...infiltrated the lnfo-Sphere
and set off his amazing bomb.
Only this time....
Thank you for saving the universe, Fry.
-Here.
-Oh, thanks.
If you ever need a savior again, just ask.
Oh, we will. We will.
I can't wait to tell
everyone what happened.
Yes. Incidentally,
I need to remain undercover. . .
. . .so I'm blanking your memory.
Did everything just taste
purple for a second?
Oh, well, let's go home,
you dumb poop machine.
[GIBBERING]
-Bender, would you do the honors?
-With gusto.
Hey, Leela. I guess I got this for you.
Oh, thank you.
You know what?
I don't care if you're not. . .
. . .the most important person
in the universe.
It really makes me happy
to see you right now.
Then I am the most important
person in the universe.
Yes!